Um, so basically...
I serve as the source of the
spirit Aishia's magical energy.
She receives magical energy through our
covenant and telepathic connection.
That may be true, but for the
two of you to be alone together...
It can have an effect on a young man.
In that case, I'll sleep with Miharu.
What? With me?
It isn't as much as Haruto, but Miharu
has a lot of magical energy, too.
Miharu-san has magic?
I don't really understand,
but if I can help, then...
S-So, Miharu-san and Aishia
will be sharing a room.
Aki-chan and Masato-kun, you're siblings,
so do you mind being in the same room?
No problem.
Just make sure you keep the room clean.
Then, Miharu-san and
Aishia can use this room.
Aki-chan and her brother can use this room.
Wow!
Professor Celia, please use this room.
All right. Well, good night.
Good night.
Spirit Chronicles 2
Oh, I see. So that's what's going on.
Okay, I get it.
I am Sakata Hiroaki!
Shopping in Another World
Ayase Miharu.
I never imagined I'd meet her in this world.
I wonder what she'd think if I confessed
that I have Amakawa Haruto's memories.
No, I'm not Amakawa Haruto anymore.
Right now, I'm living as Rio.
I made up my mind long ago to
dirty these hands of mine...
so that I can take
revenge against that man.
Amakawa Haruto is already dead.
Rio, are you awake?
Professor?
I'm sorry to bother you at this hour.
I just wanted to talk a little.
I-I'm sorry. I should
have come to call on you.
Please, come inside.
Thank you. It's been quite some time
since we last had tea together.
Yes, you're right.
So, um...
I couldn't ask this in front of everyone,
but how have you fared in the
time I couldn't see you?
Wh-Where did you meet Aishia?
O-Oh, but more importantly,
what did you mean by your "past life"?
Professor, please calm down.
Yes, you're right. I couldn't help myself.
Let's talk about one thing at a time.
First, regarding the topic that
came up with Miss Miharu
and the others, my past life.
I have the memories of another version of me.
It happens that he was from the same
world that Miss Miharu and the others are.
And that's why you understand their language.
Yes.
Professor, do you remember when
you first met me in the slums?
Of course I do.
I had regained the memories of
my past life just before that.
Really?
In my past life, my name was Haruto.
Oh, then that's why you
chose Haruto as your alias.
In my memories, I was twenty.
What? But then you're older than I am!
Yes, I suppose it might work that way.
It's true that when we first met, I thought
you were strangely mature for a little boy.
But I'm really just Rio,
so I'm sixteen years old.
Yes, you're right. Rio is Rio.
Yes.
Thank you, Rio.
What?
It's because you came to kidnap
me that I can be here with you.
I feel a sense of relief deep in my heart.
But, um, I'm worried about Father.
I wish I could at least
tell him that I'm safe.
Yes, I'm sure you do. Well, what do
you think about writing a letter?
A letter? You're right!
Tomorrow, let's buy stationery
at the Ricca Guild.
Yes, that would make me very happy!
I also have a suggestion.
Oh? What is it?
So that no one recognizes us in Amande,
Professor, you should use an alias and...
Capital of the Kingdom of Beltrum, Beltrant
Sir Charles, recent events
were quite the disaster.
Who would have imagined that your
fiancée would be kidnapped?
Master Reiss, there is no need to worry.
The brigand has been dealt with.
I've received a report that,
after being struck by Alfred's attack,
not even a trace remained.
Really?
However, I have no news
of Celia's whereabouts.
It's likely that there was an accomplice.
At present, the borders of
the capital have been closed
and a search is being conducted.
I see.
The boy and the spirit have likely
gone and concealed their location.
How truly daring of them. Well done.
But for a prophecy in the sacred
writings to come true now is simply...
A Hero has descended into
our kingdom as well,
and my father has taken custody of them.
I hope that they will become stalwart
allies of the Beltrum Kingdom.
But I thought that the Beltrum Kingdom was
in possession of another sacred stone.
Yes, it's with Princess Flora
and Duke Huguenot.
It's likely that at this very moment,
they are welcoming the Hero.
It's quite the troublesome situation.
They're already traitors for
trying to ingratiate themselves
with the Kingdom of Galarc.
Speaking of the Kingdom of Galarc,
among the guests was Liselotte Cretia
of the Ricca Merchants Guild.
I've heard she's quite a talented woman.
Yes, but she's still just a girl of fifteen.
No, no. Liselotte and the Ricca Guild
are just as great a blight as
Duke Huguenot's faction.
If measures against them aren't taken soon...
Beltrum Kingdom, Rodan Territory Capital, Rodania
Sir Hero, would you like more to drink?
Oh. Roanna, wasn't it?
Why don't you have a seat?
No, I couldn't.
It makes me feel bad to keep
a girl standing like that.
Thank you for your thoughtfulness.
Really, I never imagined I'd be able
to invite a legendary hero to my home.
It's an honor.
If there is anything at all you desire,
please let me know.
Legendary hero, huh?
This kind of stuff sure is
popular in web novels lately.
Yeah, yeah.
It's like they're written from a template!
Huh?
Who are all of you?
Where am I?
Um, my name is Flora Beltrum.
I am the second princess
of the Kingdom of Beltrum.
I serve as guardian to
Her Highness, Princess Flora.
I am Duke Gustav Huguenot.
A princess and a duke?
It's like the prologue to a
summoned-to-another-world story.
Could it be that you are... a Hero?
A hero? Me?
Y-Yes. According to the prophecy
left by the Six Wise Gods,
in their future, a thousand years
after the founding of the Holy Era,
the Heroes will appear where
the sacred stones are.
I'm... a Hero?
Yes. I took that sword to be
proof that you are a Hero.
Sword?
A-A katana?
That's a cool design!
It stirs my geeky little heart!
Oh, I see. So that's what's going on.
Okay, I get it.
This is a pretty flimsy storyline.
The fact that they understand Japanese
fulfills way too many tropes, right?
Sir Hero, may I ask your name?
Judging from this princess' reactions,
I'm certain that a Hero's
status is pretty high.
In which case...
I am Sakata Hiroaki.
Still, getting treated like an odd-job man
because I acted humble would be a pain.
If we're negotiating, then I've
gotta come out on top of these guys.
To be honest, being suddenly told
I'm a Hero has me a little confused.
This sacred stone the princess has
there is what called me here, right?
Yes, we believe so.
It called me here, right?
So, I can go back, naturally?
What? Go back?
This is a kidnapping.
I had my own life back in my world,
but it's all been forcibly stolen from me.
I-I'm sorry. These sudden
events have me at a loss, too.
I'm not blaming you for anything,
but I'm the one in a tough spot here.
Sir Hero, don't you think you're
being disrespectful to Her Highness?
Stewart!
My apologies.
Please forgive my foolish son's rudeness.
But calling it a kidnapping
is a misunderstanding.
First, I vow to tell you everything
regarding our current situation.
Will you listen to what I have to say?
Very well.
What wonderful weather for shopping!
Look after things while
we're gone, won't you?
Be careful out there, okay?
There's a barrier around this place,
but try not to leave the house, all right?
All right!
Oh!
I'll take Celia.
Wow!
Miharu-san, do you mind if
I'm the one to take you there?
I-I'd appreciate it, thank you.
Then, pardon the familiarity.
Please hold on tightly!
I-I will!
This is amazing! We're really
flying through the sky!
I think you'll enjoy the difference
in the scenery from here.
How beautiful. I've never seen
anything like this before.
You're not scared?
I'm all right as long as
I'm with you, Haruto-san.
Say, Aishia, how much do you know about Rio?
Nearly everything.
Haruto's memories flow to me
through our covenant.
So you share your memories?
Yes.
That sounds to me as if your consciousnesses
are tightly bound together.
That's the nature of a spirit covenant.
Your very spirits are bound together.
Th-That seems... unfair somehow.
No, I mean...
when I think that you know a
side of Rio that I don't...
it makes me feel a little lonely.
A side of Haruto that Celia doesn't know?
Haruto is different than he used to be.
Little by little, he is
starting to rely on others.
He is? That Rio?
He must have been lucky enough
to meet some good people.
It's thanks to you, Celia.
What?
When Haruto was all alone,
the first one to reach out to him
with kindness was you, Celia.
That's why Haruto was able
to start trusting people.
I hope you'll continue to interact
with him the way you did in the past.
Yes, of course I will.
Spirit Chronicles 2
Which is why we'd like you to refer to
Professor Celia as Cecilia, Miharu-san.
All right.
Also, let's change our hair
colors before we go into town.
Black hair is unusual, you see.
Oh, that's amazing!
You too, please, Professor. There may
be people searching for us out there.
Galarc Kingdom, Trade Town, Amande
My! It's just as lively as the rumors say.
I wonder what that line is for.
It's for a menjuu shop.
It's a local specialty.
It's basically like Japanese manjuu.
Omanjuu?
The Ricca Guild has a great variety
of foods like that and pasta
that resemble foods from Earth.
We can buy some to take back with us later.
Yes, I'd love that!
Come on in! Welcome to the Ricca Guild!
Today, I, Chloe, am in charge
of attending to our visitors!
I'm looking forward to helping you!
Then, please assist these ladies.
I will return in about an hour.
Aishia, please interpret for Miharu-san.
All right.
Then first, let's find
some changes of clothes.
Please feel free to try on
whatever you'd like!
All right! In that case,
I'll give it everything I've got!
Miharu, may I have a moment?
Cecilia-san... Oh!
What do you think? They're mage's clothes.
I think they look wonderful on you!
Miharu, you should try things on, too.
I should, too?
Miharu, everything looks lovely on you!
Does it?
Yes! You look really lovely!
I wasn't able to obtain any leads.
Well, it only happened yesterday.
I suppose there's nothing to be done about it.
Is there anything else you require?
I do need some stationery.
Then, allow me to show you the way!
I'll be back shortly!
Miharu, feel free to do as you like.
Miharu-san? Have you found
anything you'd like to—
Um, I'm sorry!
Is something wrong?
Not really.
I-It's nothing!
Um, Miharu-san, please don't worry
about me and take your time shopping.
Haruto-san, wait!
Haruto-san, will you try holding
these clothes up over those?
O-Of course.
I knew it! They suit you really well!
Do they?
Yes, those look good on you.
Miharu, you're certainly
good at picking things out.
They look incredibly good on you!
Thank you, Miharu-san.
I was just thinking that I didn't
have enough everyday clothes.
I'll take these, please.
Thank you for your purchase!
We happen to be running a gentlemen's
clothing campaign at the moment.
If you were to purchase one more ensemble,
I can give you a discount on the set.
What do you think?
That's the Ricca Guild for you!
You really are good at selling things.
In that case...
In that case, may I pick out a set this time?
By all means!
Capital of the Kingdom of Beltrum, Guest House
Lady Liselotte, it seems it
will be some time before the
kingdom's borders are reopened.
Understood, Aria.
I'm sure that Beltrum wants to control
the information on this matter.
Thanks to that, I am unable to conduct business.
I'm stuck here, as you can see.
Please take this opportunity to forget
about work and enjoy some leisure time.
Leisure time...
Well, the fact that Duke Arbor's
reputation was completely crushed
is quite amusing to the Kingdom of Galarc.
It's something to be thankful for, of course.
But I do feel sorry for the bride, Celia.
She's an old friend of yours, isn't she?
Who do you think did it?
Someone hostile to Duke Arbor's family.
Yes.
Still, to think that in the middle of
this chaos, Heroes would appear.
Talk of that abounds within the castle.
It's more than likely that a Hero has been
summoned to our Kingdom of Galarc, too!
I have to hurry up and get back.
Professor Celia and Miharu-san
picked out the clothes.
I hope they suit your tastes.
She hopes you like them.
Then I'll put mine on!
Me, too!
Oh! These are cool!
These are so cute! Thank you!
Both of you look very nice!
Unfortunately,
I couldn't find any specific information
on Satsuki-san or Takahisa-san.
I see.
But it seems to be true
that the Heroes have arrived, just as in
the legend of the Six Wise Gods.
Miharu-san, you and the others must
have gotten caught up in the summoning.
This is just my guess,
but it could be that
Satsuki-san and Takahisa-san
were summoned to this world as Heroes.
Heroes?
By heroes, do you mean like
the main characters in games?
In the prophecy, there are six Heroes.
It's possible that they are two among them.
Satsuki-neechan and my big bro are... Heroes?
If Oniichan is here in this world,
then I want to go look for him!
I understand how you feel...
but Aki-chan, I think all of you need
to learn the language and
customs of this world first.
Oh. Yes, you're right.
All right. After all, we can't
just keep depending on Ai-chan.
You mean I have to study?
Aw, man! I came all the way to another world,
but I still have to do the same stuff!
And about how we'll proceed from here...
I know some trustworthy people,
so I think we should ask for advice.
Trustworthy people?
The People of the Spirits.
I'm hungry.
I suppose we should eat.
Oh, if it's all right, I'd like to help.
Thank you. Then, why don't we
have Japanese food tonight?
Japanese food? Hooray!
"Jahpaneze" food?
The cuisine of the land where
Miss Miharu and the others lived.
Oh, I'm looking forward to that!
What do you think?
It seems just a little too light.
Then let's add a little more miso.
Miharu-oneechan isn't usually
comfortable around guys,
but she's fine with Haruto-san.
I'd like to learn to cook, too.
Professor, would you like to do this, too?
Yes!
Thank you for the meal!
Next Time
My Home, Under Attack
"My Home, Under Attack."
Spirit Chronicles 2
GROWL
Illustration: Minazuki Futago